（ナルト）たぁ～っ　悔しい！
（アオバ）ハハハッ！
♪～
The Forgotten Island
俺たちは
船を修繕しておきます。
We'll be repairing the ship.
（ヤマト）頼むよ。
Thank you.
ゲキマユ先生ってば　ここに？
Is Bushy Brow Sensei
really here?
鳥の飛び去った方向だ。
The bird flew off
in this direction.
ここが棲家と考えて
いいんじゃないか。
I think it's safe to conclude that
its nest is around here.
でも…　先生　食われちまった
ってことはないかな？
But…is there a chance that
Bushy Brow Sensei has been eaten?
いくら
船酔いで弱ってたからって→
No matter how seasick and weak he is,
he wouldn't let a bird eat him.
鳥に食われるような人じゃない。
じゃあ　俺が仙人モードで
感知してみるってばよ。
Well, I'll use Sage Mode
and see if I can find him.
待つんだ　ナルト。
Hold it, Naruto.
ここは　どんな島かわからない。
We don't know
what kind of island this is.
奥の手は温存しておくように。
Let's keep our secret weapons
in reserve.
あっ！　見ろよ　あそこ。
Look, over there.
島民がいるんだ。
俺が話を聞いてくる。
There's a native islander!
I'll go talk to her.
戻ってくるの待つ？
Are we gonna wait
until he returns?
いや　僕たちは別方向を
探しに行こう。
No.
Let's search in another direction.
待って！
Wait!
怪しい者じゃない。
I'm not anyone suspicious!
♪～
あれ？
待って！
Wait!
はっ！
螺旋丸！
Rasengan!
バカでっかい　クモだってばよ。
That's a humongous spider.
It's coming.
来る。
おう！
Right!
影分身の術！
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
– It's huge!
でけぇ！
木遁！
Wood Style!
おりゃ！
は～！
こんな大蛇と　前にも
戦ったことがあるってばよ。
I've battled a giant serpent
like this before.
Yeah. It's just like
Orochimaru's Summons.
ああ…　まるで
大蛇丸の口寄せのようだ。
あの鳥…。
ガイさんを連れていったヤツだ。
That bird!
It's the one that took Guy!
待て！
Stop!
ねぇ　キミ
聞きたいことがあるんだ。
Hey you,
can I ask you something?
俺の仲間を見なかったか？
Have you seen my friend?
あっ…。
俺たちは　はぐれた仲間を
探してるんだ。
We're looking for our friend
who got separated from us.
話を聞かせてほしいだけだよ。
I'd like to ask you
some questions.
できれば　キミのことなんかも…。
And ask about you as well.
これが何だい？
What is this?
『口寄せに関する調査　改良
及び　創造』。
"Investigation into Summoning:
Improvements as Well as Creation."
創造？
Creation?
「ここは　口寄せの島。
"This is a Summoning Island."
"Many life forms reside here that
are useful to shinobi for summoning."
忍が口寄せするに
有益な生命体が→
多数　生息している。
当初は調査のみに
留めるつもりであったが→
"At first, research was
our only purpose."
口寄せ獣が欲しいという
忍たちの需要に応えるべく→
"But to satisfy requests from
shinobi for Summoning Animals,"
"we set out to capture them."
捕獲に乗り出した。
需要が増大するなか→
"In the midst of
increasing demand,"
口寄せ獣の改良を
始めることにした。
"it was decided to begin improving
the Summoning Animals."
かけあわせによって　新たな
口寄せ獣を生み出すのである。
"Through crossbreeding,"
"new species of Summoning Animals
will also be created."
忍たちの要求が高まる。
"The demand from shinobi
is increasing."
究極の口寄せ獣はいないのかと。
"Is there an Ultimate
Summoning Animal?"
いなければ生み出すしかない」。
"If not, we will just
have to create one."
「問題は
究極獣の制御である。
"The problem is how to
suppress the ultimate animal."
コントロールには
特別な封印術が必要だろう。
"To control it, a special
Sealing Jutsu is necessary."
あるいは
人柱力のような特別な存在が。
"Or perhaps something else
that is unique like a Jinchuriki."
あの里の生き残りが
見つかればいいが」。
"It would be perfect if a survivor
of that village could be found."
あっ！　人柱力…。
Jinchuriki?
この島は　いったい？
What is this island?
おい！
Hey!
いいね？　いくよ。
おう！
Ready? Let's go.
Right!
ああ　そうだ　そうだ
タララッタ　ラッタラ　ラッタッタ。
Yes, that's right!
タララッタラ　ラッタラ　ラッタッタ！
Raise your legs higher!
もっと足上げて
タララッタラ　ラッタラ　ラッタッタ！
え…。
えっ！？
– What?
ゲキマユ先生。
おっ　お前たち。
Bushy Brow Sensei?
You guys!
こら　よせよせよせ
わかった　わかった。
Hey, stop that, you guys!
I know! I know!
何ですか　これは。
それが　なんだかな。
What's going on?
Well, it seems…
おい　よせってば　もう！
Hey! Stop, stop!
どうやら　俺は　子守りとして
連れてこられたらしい。
I've been brought here
to babysit them.
子守り！？
そんな　まさか。
Babysit?
What? That's ridiculous.
だが　俺は
食われそうになることもなく→
I'm not in any danger
of being eaten.
ここで　こうして
雛の相手をしている。
I'm just here playing
with these chicks.
ところで　ここは　どこなんだ？
By the way, where are we?
それが　僕たちにも　さっぱり。
Well, we have no idea either.
ゲキマユ先生を
追いかけてきたんだってばよ。
We came chasing after you,
Bushy Brow Sensei.
なあ　おい
なんで俺を連れてきたんだ？
Say, why did you
bring me here?
子守りだったら
他をあたってくれ。
If you want a babysitter,
find someone else.
I'm in the midst of a mission.
I must go.
俺はな　任務の最中だ
行かねばならんのだ。
ん？　乗れというのか？
What?
You want me to get on?
よし　わかった！
ちょ…　ガイさん！
Yes! All right.
Guy!
それっ！
このままでは埒があかん。
We won't learn anything
by staying here.
お前たちも一緒に来い。
えぇ！？
You two come along!
（アオバ）キミ！
You…
これは…。
This is…
なぁ　キミ　これが
究極獣ってヤツなのか？
Hey, is this the Ultimate
Summoning Animal?
なら　直接　コイツに聞いてやるさ。
Then I'll ask it directly.
うわっ　何なんだ　アイツら！？
Whoa, what are they?!
あそこに降りる気か？
Does it plan to land there?
シッ　シッ！
Shoo, shoo!
この中へか？
キーッ！
Inside here?
ここ火山だろ　火山！
This is a volcano! A volcano!
さっきから何だよ　この声？
What the heck is that voice?
木遁！
Wood Style!
行ってみましょう。
おう！
Let's go and see!
Right!
え～っ　行くの！？
We're going?!
ああ　もう　来るな！
Hey, stay away!
放っておこう
僕らを襲う気配はない。
Ignore them.
They're not showing signs
that they want to attack us.
コイツ　食ったってのか？
No way...
It was eating them?
The other animals…
他の生物を　島の口寄せ獣を…。
The Summoning Animals
of this island?
((ダメです　制御できません！
It's not working.
We can't control it.
ホノカ！　封印だ　早く封印を！
Honoka! The seal!
Hurry and seal it!
うわ～っ！
ホノカ　なんとか止めろ！
Honoka! Do something
to make it stop!
ダメ　おさえきれない！
I can't. I can't suppress it.
(助けて　誰か助けて！))
Help… Someone, help me!
コイツ　食うだけ食って
眠りに入ったのか！
This thing ate everything in sight,
and then went to sleep.
さなぎになって
成体になるのを待ってる。
Now it's a chrysalis
waiting to mature.
じゃあ　キミは…。
（ガイ）アオバ！
Then that means you're…
Aoba!
ガイさん　無事だったんですね！
そんなことより　ここは？
Guy! You're alive.
Never mind that.
What is this place?
究極の口寄せ獣を
生み出そうとした→
It seems to be a research facility to
create Ultimate Summoning Animals.
研究施設のようです。
そして　その研究成果が…。
And the result of the research…
何だ　こりゃ！？
What is this?
どこの忍かまでは
わかりませんが→
I'm not sure where
these shinobi were from,
究極の口寄せ獣を求め
研究を続けた結果→
but they were conducting research
on Summoning Animals.
自ら他の獣を取り込み
己の能力にしてしまう→
And it seems they've created
the Ultimate Summoning Animal
that feeds on other animals and
assimilates their abilities into its own.
究極獣を生み出したようです。
何？　コイツ生きてんの？
おそらく…。
What? This thing is alive?
Probably…
しかも
研究員たちまで飲み込み→
Furthermore, it swallowed up
the researchers
更に進化しようとしている。
アイツら！
and is trying to further evolve.
Th-Those guys…
何だ！？
生まれるのか？
What's happening?!
Is it about to be born?
これが　究極の口寄せ獣ですか。
So this is the Ultimate
Summoning Animal?
Well, it just looks like
a giant greedy monster to me.
俺には食い意地の張った
でかいバケモンにしか見えねえ。
どうする　誰か契約してみるか？
What will we do? Anyone want to try
entering into a contract with it?
そんな雰囲気じゃありませんよ。
It's in no mood for that!
くる！
It's coming!
は～！　とう！
うお！
クソッ　たあ！
Damn!
クモの糸だと？
Spider thread?
さっきのクモの能力を
とり込んだんです。
It assimilated the abilities of
that spider it devoured earlier.
飢餓感…　飢えだ。
It's hungry?
It's starving.
食っても食っても
満たされない思い。
No matter how much it eats,
it still feels hungry.
すべてを食い尽くそうという
欲求しかない。
All it knows is a desire
to eat everything in sight.
口寄せ獣としちゃあ
失敗作ってことか！
In other words, it's a failure
of a Summoning Animal.
だが　対忍用に
特別に作られている。
However, it was created specifically
for use against shinobi.
油断するな！
Don't let your guard down!
Wood Style!
木遁！
ヤマト隊長　さすが！
Right on, Captain Yamato!
チャクラを吸いとられた。
It sucked out my chakra!
So that's what "created specifically
for use against shinobi" means.
対忍用というのは
こういうことか。
なら仙人モードで
ぶっとばしてやるってばよ！
I'll pulverize it with
my Sage Mode!
Naruto's Sage Mode requires time
to absorb Nature Energy.
ナルトの仙人モードは
自然エネルギーの吸収に時間がかかる。
Let's cover him!
カバーしましょう。
Eight Inner Gates!
Fifth Gate!
八門遁甲　第五社門　開！
Open!
たあ！
いける！
I can do this!
幻術を使うのか！
It's using genjutsu!
うわあ！
Hang in there, Guy!
ガイさん　しっかり！
不覚をとった。
That was an
embarrassing defeat!
ナルト　幻術だ。
Naruto! It's genjutsu!
はっ　あんなのが幻術使うなんて
思わねえってばよ！
I can't believe that thing
can use genjutsu!
うわあ！
Lightning Style?!
雷遁だって？
忍術も使うんだ。
It uses ninjutsu too.
We don't know what other abilities
it has up its sleeve!
どんな手の内を隠し持ってるか
わからないぞ。
はっ　溶岩だ
さっきのあの入り口の！
Lava!
There…by the back entrance!
I see.
なるほど　あそこへ叩き落とせば
ひとたまりもあるまい。
If we can drop that thing
into the lava, it's over.
Wood Style: Domed Wall!
木遁　木錠壁！
ナルトは仙人モードを！
うん。
Naruto, go into Sage Mode!
All right, here I go!
よっしゃ　いくぞ！
うお～っ！
木ノ葉剛力旋風　とりゃっ！
Severe Leaf Hurricanes!
どうだ！
How was that?!
♪～
クッ！
翼！？
Wings?!
えいっ！
うおぉ！
逃がさんぞ！
I won't let you escape!
とうっ！
逃げる気か！
Is it trying to run away?!
If we let something
like that loose…
あんなヤツを野放しにしたら…。
どういうことだってばよ？
What's going on?
食われた仲間の敵討ちか？
Are they trying to avenge
the others who were eaten?
危ない！　下がって！
Watch out! Get back!
あっ　キミは　やはり…。
I knew it
アオバさん　なぜ止めないんです！
あれは　彼女が残した思念だ。
えっ！？
♪～
ナルト　今だ！
風遁　螺旋手裏剣！
はぁ～っ！
♪～
（ホノカ）ありがとう。
＜季節のご飯が大好きな豆助＞
≫はーい　お待たせ～
できたわよ
クゥ～ン
＜　それは　この魚の旬の到来を
日本人の誰もが待ちわびた→
待ちわびた…秋の味覚
その名は…＞